<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<node name="/Telepathy_Logger"
  xmlns:tp="http://telepathy.freedesktop.org/wiki/DbusSpec#extensions-v0">
  <tp:copyright>Copyright © 2009 Collabora Ltd.</tp:copyright>
  <tp:license xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    <p>This library is free software; you can redistribute it and/or
modify it under the terms of the GNU Lesser General Public
License as published by the Free Software Foundation; either
version 2.1 of the License, or (at your option) any later version.</p>

<p>This library is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the GNU
Lesser General Public License for more details.</p>

<p>You should have received a copy of the GNU Lesser General Public
License along with this library; if not, write to the Free Software
Foundation, Inc., 51 Franklin Street, Fifth Floor, Boston, MA 02110-1301, USA.</p>
  </tp:license>
  <interface name="org.freedesktop.Telepathy.TelepathyLoggerService.DRAFT"
    tp:causes-havoc="experimental">
    <tp:added version="0.1">(as a draft)</tp:added>

    <tp:struct name="Chat_Message_Field" array-name="Chat_Message_Field_List">
      <tp:member type="s" name="Sender">
        <tp:docstring>
          The identifier of the contact who originated this message.
        </tp:docstring>
      </tp:member>
      <tp:member type="s" name="Message">
        <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        The body of the message sent to a 1-1 Chat or a Chat Room.
        </tp:docstring>
      </tp:member>
      <tp:member type="u" name="Timestamp">
        <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
        Unix timestamp for the log entry
        </tp:docstring>
      </tp:member>
      <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>It represents a single message, received or sent.</p>
      <p>The receiver is implicit in the request: if the sender is the user,
      the receiver is the identifier in chat_id paramenter, if the sender is
      not the user, the user is consequently the receiver of the message<p>
      </tp:docstring>
    </tp:struct>

    <method name="LastChats"
      tp:name-for-bindings="LastChats">
      <arg direction="in" name="Account" type="o" tp:type="Contact_Handle[]">
        <tp:docstring>
          An array of handles representing contacts.
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <arg direction="in" name="Identifier" type="s"
        tp:type="Contact_Info_Map">
        <tp:docstring>
          A dictionary mapping contact handles to information, whose keys are
          the subset of the requested list of handles for which information was
          cached.
        </tp:docstring>
      </arg>
      <tp:docstring>
        Request the last Lines entries of logs for the specified couple Account+Identifier.
      </tp:docstring>
    </method>

    <tp:docstring xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
    An interface for requesting informatiosn about the Telepathy Logger entries.
    </tp:docstring>
  </interface>
</node>
<!-- vim:set sw=2 sts=2 et ft=xml: -->
